Sajal Birla

+91-9571132777 | sajalbirla71@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/sajalbirla | github.com/sajalbirla

Summary

Highly determined and user-focused Front-end Developer with a wealth of experience in constructing single-page applications and multi-platform websites using Responsive Web Design. Proficient in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and ReactJs, adapt at transforming designs into fully functional UI components. Collaborative and solution-driven, with a keen eye for detail and a pass on for continuous learning strategies.

EDUCATION

Swami Keshvanand Institute of Technology (SKIT)

Jaipur, Rajasthan

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science

Aug. 2018 - June 2022

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Jan 2022 – Present

 $BigStep\ Technologies$

Gurugram, India

- Proficient in utilizing WebRTC to capture and optionally stream audio and video media.
- Executed RESTful API's to make HTTP requests for fetching and submitting data to the backend.
- Built reusable code for future use and optimized web pages for 5 applications for maximum speed & scalability.
- Worked with UI/UX design teams to improve existing applications and increase conversion rates by 20%.
- Integrate real-time Google Analytics on the website for live traffic monitoring, user count, average visit duration, and click-through analysis.
- Enhanced a login authorization component to provide different login types based on the type of user accessing
- Developed and implemented multiple dynamic and browser-compatible web pages utilizing HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and React (Redux), resulting in a 40% increase in page loading speed and a 25% decrease in bounce rate.

Frontend Developer

July 2021 - Nov 2021

Okhla, New Delhi

Ameyatrix Business Solutions Pvt. Ltd

- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to enable seamless payment processes from customers to merchants.
- Built extensive test coverage for all new features, reducing the number of customer complaints by 10 %.
- Optimising components for maximum performance across a vast array of web-capable devices & browsers by 50%.
- Crafted Controlled Web & App interfaces to enhance the overall customer experience.
- Implemented a fraud and risk detection system for payment transactions, ensuring secure and reliable financial
 operations.

Projects

Web Application Current Weather of Any City | HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, ReactJs & API

- Utilized OpenWeatherMap's API to fetch and innovative current weather data.
- Applied Modern Javascript with React hooks and conditionals for efficient data retrieval.
- Developed a user-friendly interface allowing users to input any city and receive a visually appealing weather response.

React Expense Manager web Application | HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, ReactJS & API

- Using React hooks and conditional we can input the detail of your Expense and store it in a Storage.
- Designed and Expanded an Expense Manager web application to track income and expenses with local storage functionality.
- Collaborated with administrators to suggest features and get feedback about the Expense Manager web Application.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: C/C++, Python, JavaScript

Web Technologies: HTML5, CSS, Jquery, TypeScript

Frameworks:ReactJs, NodeJs, Angular, , Material-UI, FastAPI, NextJs Database Management System : MYSQL (8.0.22), MongoDb Soft skills: Communication, Leadership, Problem-solving, Creativity Developer Tools: Git, Docker, VS Code, Visual Studio, IntelliJ